employing new principles
and tomorrow we'll have a talk of a
different kind. How to apply the same principle
to your
relationships. Today is about how to make
money, create
privacy. Today is
talking about making a
million, but then a friend of
Li's said
this with
oxygen. What does this mean, money like
oxygen? When you come into this room,
so beautiful and so
new, and you
sit down and you're
breathing, you didn't come in asking if there will be enough oxygen. No
one goes to lie in their room
thinking, "Will there be enough oxygen?"
until
tomorrow. No one stays up all night
worrying about whether there will be enough
oxygen.
I believe that material resources like
money are the
same thing, so we're getting together now to
talk about
it, and I want to help you with
that. I want you to have access to this
similar money. It
means you have
enough all the
time and don't worry. In
my own
case, I don't care if I have a
million. I have other things.  Things in my life, for
a while, I have resources
and there are
things I like, for example, being generous by
giving
money. I like to travel to
various
countries. I don't need a very
big house, but I like to
meditate. I like to read
books. I like to
translate, and for that, I want a
comfortable place. I personally tried to live
in a
cave about 20 years
ago. I found a very good
cave and thought, "This cave is going to be very
peaceful." But then a rattlesnake
appeared, a
green one. If you die there, you
die there.
Then first
a coyote
appeared. In the
cave, I meditated, and there were tarantulas, spiders
walking like
spiders. They run like
in novels, in
storybooks. A cave sounds very exotic,
romantic, but now I have
a very small one, very small, in the
mountains, very
calm, very
beautiful. I can walk to the
river, I can even take off all my clothes. There's no
place
[Music]
with oxygen. I don't have
money. I do
n't have a
paycheck, and that gives my mind a lot of
free space, and I can dedicate my life to doing other
things. I said, but you won't be able to
So I'm going to sow the
seeds for this
money.
Some of the people here are like
José and the
university
now.
[Music] There are
4 buildings
and no tuition is charged to
attend a
university. So far, the
teaching is free. The buildings,
the
land, everything is a few
million.
A loan to buy the
land that has been paid off. We are
also
sad that this is
thanks to sowing the
seeds for this
economic prosperity. So today we are going to talk
about making
money, but please, it's not about making
money. It's
if you want to do a big project like this.
You need
money and you can sow the seeds to
generate
money in this
month or in the next 10 or 20
years
when thousands of
people will hear great ideas, will
be able to listen to beautiful
music, will be able to see the plays.
And so to help these
people, we built this
stage. The people who come here never
think about everyone who participated in the
construction of this, like the
workers, the laborers,
the students. Many times they are like
your own
children.
Many people work many years to be here.
[Music]
Val, like many people who worked for
many years to build it,
investing millions of
dollars, so people like you or
me should be
builders. Let's build things
for
future generations, like the university in
Arizona. Everyone complains about the
food,
but nobody stops to think that it
cost millions of dollars to build the
place. So if you have a
dream in your life to help other
people
anonymously, then it's good if you know
how to create causes to generate
money, and you can sow money, and I'm going to teach you
how to sow money,
and that way you can fulfill and have
big dreams. For example, with my company,
we are helping
Tibetan refugees. This year marks 25 years
[Music].
Many
constructions in the
camps, and we have put
computers on the internet,
reading the various books of wisdom of
Hanua, and in 25
years we have completed nearly a thousand
pages,
and we put them on the
internet. And the book that many of
you have acquired,
Hanua
Diamond Cutter, this book is based on one
of those
books, but in these 25 years of work
writing, we have only been able to cover
7% of what we have
available. At this rate, this project is not
going to  to culminate but the next 150 years, so for
that it has to
have
economic resources to be able to continue paying and
helping the Tibetan refugees who
work with it. So I
think that until there are
poor people in the
world, we must learn to
sow the seeds of
economic prosperity so that we can
help. So today we are going to talk
about
money. We are not talking about a
person, the big fish and
corrupt officials,
but we are talking about how to use
the money generated to help other
people, and for that it is very good to have
money. So let's begin.
First, I would like to tell you
my
story. I don't want to boast,
no, what I want is for you to understand that you can
also do the
same. We can have the first
slide
[Music] of
the university
when I was
young. I lived in a very
poor family, but I got a
scholarship to study at [unclear], and
my family was very happy, and
I was very
happy. And then I even went to the White House,
to the President of the United States.
[Music]
medal, [unclear] ...
At first,
because it made her very
happy. Then my heart kind of
broke, and after a
while, they called me again and said, "
Now your father is
dead." I had three
brothers. My brother was
sad because of
that, and so I was so
sad. I wasn't so happy anymore.
I wanted to stay at university and make my parents
proud, but now they're gone. So I did
n't know what to
do. Then, while I was going to
a
class, there was a boy in my class who was
of
Indian origin, and so I was running to the classroom
because I'd
never felt like I was in that building.
[Music]
And if you want to understand
life, it's what happened with my
mother when she
died.
Then your mind kind of
opens up. Now, the
world economy. There are
good people who think
differently. Then a
tragedy.
Then she told me, "But don't
worry, I'm going to India before
you." I said, "
Okay." Then I asked the
university if I could have
a year's leave of absence. Within the
law, I said, "
Then I'm
leaving from New
York. The plane goes up and then it
crashes. All the
Italian ladies and  Then it fell again, then it
began
[Music] to
ascend. I had
taken a candora with water
with me
because... and then
we learned... we tied up in
India. They opened the
door. I remember the wind coming in
through the
door and it smelled like incense, a
beautiful, very
spiritual smell. I got off the
plane and it was like the temperature outside was
about 45 degrees Celsius.
Now I could see
45 million
people. The drains were open with
pigs, chickens,
cows. I ran to a small
hotel
because I didn't go out
and it was from India. I waited at the airport, he
never
appeared. I went
to the address he gave me and they
told me they never came. I was scared. I did
n't know what to
do and my plane ticket was months away
until I could return. I didn't want to go out.
Then the hotel owner came to my
room. I had eaten...
because
[Music]
I went out with the Buddhist people. He
looked at his
watch and said, "A little
late. The Buddhist people left
years ago. There are no Buddhists in
India. There are
how many
[Music]
Tibetans have come here. I try to
find out about
Tibet and in the
monoset training that culminates with
the title..."
After 25 years, one has
special exams at my
monastery. At that
time, there were 3500
mones for the examination. The
assessments.
This is what a Tibetan exam looks like: they
argue, debate, and each person asks a
question. Then we'll show a
little bit of Tibet. Ask the
questions, and that's the people
watching. If you make a
mistake, everyone will give you
quite
[Music]
frightening looks. My nickname at the monastery
is and it means
yellow. It means
jelly, gel, tea, as well as
jelly. And so, the exam lasts three weeks,
the final examination. And I finished,
and they
sat me down. And so, when you get one of those
yellow zeros, that's it. When I passed the
examination, I was so happy. I had
finished. Supposedly, you're going to
relax for the rest of your
life just drinking
tea. Sometimes you have to teach a little bit of
the
courses. Then I'm so happy thinking, "
Ah, now I'm going to be able to stay in the
monastery for the rest of my life."
[Music]
And
then,
Tom, we have
tea. Call
young man with the
message and
say, and the
office.
You have to visit your parents for a
week. You have to ask them...
ask for permission,
and the second
reason is if you make a big mistake in the
monastery, you also go to the office,
and there are four very
big monks who
grab you, put you down, and take off your
habits, showing your butt. I did
n't know why he was
calling me. I was a little
nervous,
so I went up.
You have to bend down,
but it's a cultural custom
when you want to show a lot of
respect, and that's done to show
respect.
And he told me, "Look, our monastery is
600 years
old. You are the first Westerner to
complete the entire
process of this
examination. So for you, we have a
second examination."
You said, "A
second
examination? You are a special case." You have to go to
New York City, studying in a certain
kind of
environment. At that
time,
a
business... 25 years... we have
taught you how to change the
future, how to sow what will happen
a year
later. That is what we have
taught you. Now, New York is going to be your
laboratory. That is going to be your
exam. You have  You have to start a company and
in a
year you have to have made a million dollars,
but
we are proud. The
money generated has to be
given to the people
who need it.
There are many ways to
procrastinate. And then a
teacher
said, "This is your business plan."
This is the oldest text in the
world and images of the
original copy in the
British Museum. He told me I should start a
business with diamonds
because this is the sutra that cuts the
diamond. This is going to be my
business plan. So I read the
book. It's like a trip, an
LCD trip. You don't understand
anything. It's a
discussion between Bu and Estudio,
and Bu
says, "I have a question for you,
teacher. You know, it's a
mountain. I have a
question. Is the mountain
big because
the mountain, mountain, business
plan?"
Many people
started to
start
the
business. It began with a loan of
soles.
A
loan in the
United States, second-
hand, when in the United States, the father of
a family  He
died, he donated, he
bought a
company that he bought a million dollars in 2009. He is the third
man in the
world.
And a company asked if he could write a
book.
And then people started to read this
book and they asked me if I could come and
tell
them about the Sura system
and they would try it.
And then I started going to many
countries. In New York, I think about 7 years
ago, I gave a talk like this, the same
talk, and there were two ladies sitting at the
front and they were just
secretaries at an
advertising company, all day
just
typing, but she was tired of typing, it was
boring. One of them shows me some
cones.
And then she and her
friend started their own
company,
renting a pretty
cheap, dirty apartment, a
very
small, dirty place, and they started their
business, but they only employed the
diamond cutter system. Ah, what does their
company look like? That's their
building now. Their company is now valued
at one billion
dollars and it's
called [Company Name]. You can look it up on the
internet now. The kids are running
around the building.
[Music]
Playing
jt. So my
dream, what I do  With my
life, I think for the last few
years I've simply been going to different
countries all over the world,
China, we just came from
Russia, Canada,
to Hong
Kong, and teaching people
how to sow the seeds of success.
And that's what I want to do today. It's
a
new system, it's a
different system, but you can
learn it and it will help you in your
life. Many of us spend a lot of
time at work.
[Music]
Many people spend more time at their
jobs than at
home. If you learn this
system, you can make money easily
and you can spend more time with your
[Music]
family. At the end of my involvement in
this diamond business, I
could relax and
do other things I wanted to
do for the next few months. So that's what we
mean when we talk about money being
like
oxygen, and I want to teach you
how to
do it. I was in China a few years
ago, a very large group of businessmen,
and a woman raised her hand and
[Music]
asked me, "I don't need
money, but I want a
husband. Can the
Diamond Cutter System be used to find a
husband?"
Thousands of people in
China now... [Music]... Let's do it.
I don't need a husband, I already have
a
husband.
Use the...  Diamond Cutting System
to Fix Your
Husband [Music] can make your husband
level up after class, negotiate first
class, someone, I've been married for 25
years
and for 25 years my husband hasn't
once helped wash the
dishes, is it possible to change an
old problem that one has with the
Diamond Cutting System? I said
yes, then we're going to do all that
tomorrow. There's an idea that you have to
understand and if you understand
you can sow
money, you can sow
love, talking about fixing the husband,
fixing the
wife,
we're going to talk about that tomorrow. Some
people don't care
[Music]
dined to
slow, fix the world. With these
principles you
can, yes, use these principles with
the economic situation and with your partner to
start. You're going to be able to apply this
same thing to
bigger things. So today we're going to start
talking about
money,
tomorrow we'll talk about husband, husband,
partner, but ultimately what we're
aiming for is to talk about the
world and
inner peace. We're going to take
a, I'd like,
about 5 minutes, more or less, it's
okay, for 5
minutes, observe
carefully. That's the
main idea. If you understand this
idea you can  Sow
money, you can sow a
husband, you can sow
peace. So let's talk about that for 5
minutes. Observe
[Music]
carefully.
How the
rules about the
rules. If you
understand them, you'll be able to make more
money, or you can change the way you are.
Four
steps. Number
one: what you
want is the same thing you have to
give to another
person. Jesus
said, "You do
n't have bananas from a
mango tree." Something like that.
And it means that what you
want is the same thing you have to
sow. Others:
if you want
money, you have to find a person
who, for example, wants to start their
own business.
If I feel
lonely, if I want a
partner, I must then find a
lonely person who wants company,
a
partner. If I want more
energy, if I want to feel
younger, I need to find a person who
needs more energy, more
youth. It's always the same
thing. That's rule number
one. Rule number
two,
the second
rule: This is an image of the cells
in your
body. Each circle is a
cell. Inside your
body, there are 100 trillion
cells inside your
body, but where did they come from?
[Music] From
your Father,
and
ah
Another
place. Then those two
parents, the
power to make trillions
of 50 years,
break seeds in
mind.
[Music]
[Music] I
sow the
seed,
but it will
return
money that we're
also going to talk about how to generate
a good
partner. It's just a
good
[Music]
only with it. It
returns. If you help a person who
feels lonely for a few
days, you're going to generate a
partner for about two or three
years. It's very
interesting. The second rule is that it
always
multiplies. It's very
interesting. Our company, for
example, is the
largest growing production company in history.
York, annual growth of
100% every
year. 15
[Music]
years. You
have to hire and
train, and the
opposite, feed so that it becomes what
you want. It's precisely what you have to make
easy for someone else, but with
technique you're
doing. You can sow a
small seed, but it could grow
to a
million.
It's about 70 years old
[Music] to
do this kind
of
And
I always feel a little bad in his
class because he's very demanding, he works
very
hard, and when it's over, I feel very
happy. But during class, a guy came up
to
me. "
Hey, can I shake your hand?
I want to
thank you. You're doing a great
job all over the
world, and I'm happy about
that." And his
name is [unclear]. I
received [unclear]. The next
day I
met him. [unclear]
because you didn't thank me. I
replied, "Why?" He
asked, "Look in your
backpack." In
my backpack, I always carry my
computer and other things. It's
my
office. I don't have an office. An
office is
called an office in several
cities.
Free coffee. I don't have one. I
go and he said, "
Look, backpack is like your
wallet." [unclear] extending, I
find an envelope. [unclear] The envelope is
inside.
I replied, "Whatever." Then I donated it to the university, and we made the water system for many of the [Music] buildings. It's that if you plant a seed with the right technique, the money will come to you, and you won't even be able to avoid it. So, I left the diamond business in
1999, but I
'm still involved. I even
have
businesses.
[Music]
You know, a lot. You should do
good deeds. You listen to other
people, but not  Think about what you need
if with a
tonic you can
stop it's
said even even you
can
give
back
[Music]
giving
back is fine you can give again and even
more
[Music]
so I continually
say this is what we are going to teach you
and all my friends who are in Lima are
going to
help me and I am going to teach them the technique
[Music]
you can say my mother but my mother gave
a lot of money to people my
brother gave money to my cousin to my uncle to
his
sister everyone asked
my
mother for money I gave to everyone
but look she didn't get a million for nothing It's that she
lacked the
technique there is a technique to
do that I'm going to teach you now in the
afternoon we are going to do
then
first is
that if you plant a watermelon watermelon
is what you sell that is what you
will harvest not a
banana
So you have to plant what
you want Because what you want is what you have to
give to
another number
two all the seeds multiply number two
correctly
[Music]
ice cream
with
in the term  English for the gorilla that
we call is that they bounce you
and your bounce makes you bounce because they bounce you.
One day I was in
Ireland and in Ireland they like to
drink. I was walking along the
path and suddenly there was a guy who flew from
the door
and fell in the street.
[Music]
We're going to go
back and I'm going to
ask you, did you make more money this
year? Is your husband washing the
dishes? Some people
will say that the
husband is washing all the dishes, he's
even cooking a
little, but other
people will say I still have my
husband. I
started the business but I didn't dedicate
time to it,
so he'll come with me.  or next
year if next year there is the same
question
gorilla
[Music]
passer number
if not
number
one if you want watermelons plant
watermelons if you want
money you have to plant
money number
two you don't have to give
much if you understand the technique
properly you can give even a
little and up to 200 million could
come
step number
three if you plant the seed
correctly you wo
n't be able to hide it you won't be able to
avoid it if you tell me what the step is
[Music]
could be that if you don't plant the
seed
or if you don't plant the seed with
the
correct technique nothing will
happen if I have a
watermelon seed it's a good
seed but if I try to plant it
here nothing will
happen because you have to do it with
technique so after
lunch and with the help of my friends from
Lima here there are people whom I have
taught for a long time and they are
instructors and
together this
afternoon we are going to teach you with
technique
[Applause]
we start at 3 but not the
Peruvian
[Music]
master and I said the monaster  dich un
business and said Well,
simply then a
[Music]
prun tio
Tom [Music]
est
[Music]
minutes I need
quick you can mana
leres ridit
pasama
This is based on a book that is
centuries old, it is
called and those are the names of the
four steps that are
used. Yeah, it
means one of them we are going to
teach today. D We are on page C
[Music]
queer,
but you have to say it in one
sentence what it is you
want. That is step number
[Music]
one. Then he said, My friends, what is it you
want? Tell me in one [Music]
sentence
without the [Music] words,
just one sentence. But
during the
first one, someone
asked, I have a
problem. D is the [Music]
things. You have to pick one
thing. Start with a problem,
one thing that you really
[Music]
want. Let's say you want to do a
business and I want to do a
mill. That is step
number [Music]. Step number
two is a
place.
Before anything else,
before you plant the
seed, you have to
think about where to plant the
seed. And that means  You ca
n't plant the seed in
yourself, you need another
person. That's what the other person is like:
the soil.
So you have to
think that you are
[Music] the same thing.
So if you want to
start a business, you need another
person
[Music] who wants to start a business,
and then you find this person, let's say,
a place where
you can
[Music] start.
You make a plan in your
mind. I'm going to take my
friend [Music] to
start a
business. I'm going to do that
kind of
planning in your
mind. It's a kind of
meditation. You can plant many
[Music]
seeds
together. I said yesterday, but I'm saying
[Music]
now, meditation for us is
a
tool like a
microscope, a
telescope. It's like knowing how to read.
If you don't know how to
read and you walk down the
street and you see many
signs but you don't know what they
mean, it's like being blind.
You're blind to
those things. So without
meditation, there are also many things that you wo
n't be able to
see. So in our university, in
business, we also teach
meditation, and it's not
religious
[Music]
concept.  A
business that you want to generate a little
money, then I'm going to tell you, you
can hire a building,
rented, so simply
suggestions. Every time you say a
sentence, I know a building that can be
rented, you are sowing seeds at every
instant. In that span of
time, you are creating approximately 600
different mental impressions. Ah,
simply by talking to your
friend
[Music],
while you are
talking, you are at the same time
planting
seeds.
We are
strange when we want to start our
own
business. When we are writing
our own doctoral thesis, we do
n't pay attention to
other
people's affairs. It's very
important to have a good doctoral thesis, a
degree, and the last
thing is that
people don't do much
when starting their own
[Music]
business. If we
are with our
businesses, we are only focused on
our own
business. That won't work, but in this
system, that is a serious
fault because if you concentrate only on what
you
need, you are not sowing
any seeds. However, if you help another
person, then you are sowing
seeds.
So in Step
Three, you can go for a two  hours a
week to spend all my time with
them. A friend in Buenos
Aires, I'm going to see him the day after
tomorrow, and he
told me he wants to start a real estate business
in southern Patagonia,
Argentina. So how could he
start? I
gave him help. Someone
else who wants to start the
business, and he said, "But well, there's a
problem. The problem is, I have no money.
So how can I help someone else? I don't have
money, not even a million
dollars." He
only had his laptop as an office. An even
more
beautiful story: he married the
woman and...
So you have to find
someone here you can
help if you want to do this
system. And then step number...
This is a very...
secret step. I used to go to my job every
day, two hours to
get there on the
bus. It was a disaster
until I got to
work, and we weren't allowed to
stay and live in the
offices. If I worked in New
York, I'd find a monastery near that
place.
Then I'd go every time for
hours
and return another
hour...
when a
monkey... Watch TV like that,
but the high... allowed to watch
TV... one day back home and it's
upstairs. How  I can go into his
room, I'm going to make some
coffee, a nice coffee, good coffee.
F to his room
door
[Music]
means and
car
that Tom the coffee
is watching the
curtain and so slowly
Fu and always had his
rosary doing some mantras with
it
[Music]
and he liked it a lot
B is
looking at
my time for Med
[Music]
H
or nobody sits in that
[Music]
house
and for an
hour see the pid that you do something
wrong
[Music]
ent when you have to
want because you
can And then the
rosary beads will leave red marks on the
forehead sit on
[Music]
the But I like the
floor and if they happen to ask you Three
times you get the
goal is a
tradition enteno Fu I sat on the
sofa Put your feet on the
[Music]
sofa your feet
are considered culturally to be like
very dirty very
profane you can't even sit like that
pointing showing your feet to others
is considered very
appropriate put your feet on the s I
want
[Music]
meditate the other like this like this no
no grow your
legs Lie down on the
sofa now hold your
head
look and
relax Have
coffee And if I drop one of
[Music]
coffee
when you give money if a
seed is
[Music]
small your mother gave money to many
people but didn't make 200 million as a
result this morning we mentioned
that for it to work you have to
understand the technique and what is the
technique step number
two step number
what is
two
think about helping another
person
[Music]
serenity the seeds remain in the
mind remain in the core of the
mind when you are thinking about helping
another
person you are very close to the
seed storehouse of your
mind So it is much more
powerful if you want faster results
the technique
is to spend a lot of
time making the
plan who I am going to
help where to what state I am going to
take it is it is Step number
two
talk to your
friend there is not much
time and there are many
seeds and  Those seeds are
talking, they're not as powerful as the
mind. You can make even more seeds in
step two,
mental planning, than in step three, the
physical or verbal act of
doing it. Then you go home and do
the coffee meditation.
Those meditations, those seeds, are
even more
powerful. That's the
technique. How to make 200 million
dollars. People ask what your
secret is: the coffee meditation.
[Music]
So today we're going to
practice. We're going to do the
planning meditation, and we're going to do the
coffee meditation, and you're going to be able to see how to
do it. So we're going to do
one and then another.
So we're going to
[Music] get
comfortable. You're going to
jump your hands, you're going to
close your
eyes, you're going to close your eyes, we're going to
jump your hands, we're going to put them
on your
legs, relax a little bit, we're
going to do a very
deep breath, we're going to exhale all the air we
can, and you're going to visualize how the air
goes in and out through your nose. Just stay
still. We jump our
shoulders, we release the muscles of the face, the space between our eyebrows,
we relax our
eyes, we relax our
mouths, we
relax a little bit.
[Music]
arms and we simply continue.
The
breath, we relax our legs, our
feet,
and visualize how the air enters and
leaves.
Anything that comes to mind, let's not try
not to think about it, we
simply observe, relax, and
return to
breathing.
We are going to think about that
person, that
other person, that you have to
find.
For that person, maybe they
are going through a very
sad time, maybe they lost their
job, maybe
their boyfriend or girlfriend left them, maybe they are very
sad, try to find that
person you love very much, and
you want them to feel
good.
Imagine, you are going to identify their
problem
and you are going to think about how you are going to be able to
help them, where you are going to help them, what
you can do for
them. Once you have the person in
front of you, you are imagining them, you are
seeing them there, you
are seeing their clothes, their
face, you can see their expression,
that they have a problem or that they are sad
or that they need something or someone, maybe someone to
listen to them, and you are going to say what you
are going to do: I am going to meet them, I am going to call them and I am
going to take them to a Starbucks or I am going to
take them to a coffee shop they like the most. You
are
visualizing all of that.  And you
take her, you
invite her, you sit down comfortably in the
café.
Perhaps you
ask yourself what she wants, you
make her feel comfortable,
and you sit down as you
listen to her. Visualize how this person is
talking to you, telling you their
problem. You're even
sad.
Well, you
listen
and visualize
how you give them the perfect
advice, the words that person
needs. You visualize yourself, you visualize
this person listening
attentively. Maybe now they're starting
to
smile. Your advice is
perfect,
powerful. You're imagining all of this,
visualizing it in your
mind. You're planting this
powerful seed in your
mind. You see that this
person is making a difference, even telling a
joke in your conversation that made them
feel
better. And you see now
how they smile, how they have a
light, a very beautiful light. They're
calmer. You're also smiling
in some
way. You feel
that you're helping them, you're making them feel better.
What
problem is this? The
light
slowly fades,
little by little, and arms open, opening their
eyes. This
powerful feeling is
called
coffee meditation, a very nice way of
relaxing in an armchair or
in bed, ideally. And well,
now here, sitting, closing your eyes.  Eyes in
the best of cases and imagine something we are
going to do next. So
we close our eyes for a
minute, the
body, head, face, shoulders, legs, the
whole
body calm, followed by
calm breathing that we are going to
observe.
Once we are calm,
we think of
something we have
done for other
people, a person we have cared for who has been
in
difficulty, who has been alone, going through a
bad time, depressed or
crying,
and that we have helped, assisted,
and have been able to
see how they
changed, how all their
suffering was. We visualize
that; it can be any kind of
case, it can be a big and
significant act or even a
small thing, but the important thing is to
rejoice. For example, going to
sleep, we visualize
this and we fall asleep in this
way, seeing how the person
changes
at that
moment, that act of generosity that we
have done is growing and
multiplying as if it were the light that
grows and grows and
grows. If at any moment while
doing this we are not
concentrating, we return to the
breathing, observing, we have to
concentrate well
again and we establish sleep
in that
way. This here is not any kind of
pride
or feeling  of
superiority. It is simply rejoicing
in a
virtuous action we have done to
multiply it.
[Music] We
concentrate, we relax in this
disposition, the
concentrated self, relaxed, and having felt
that we have absorbed the
virtuous result of everything we have done
that day. Regarding the help of this
person, we can the next day do
this
practice again to
maximize all its
benefit. We go and rest and
continue as much as possible in this
state of rejoicing in this result.
[Music] We
visualize how the
person
has changed and was not...